Guide to the Harry Weinberger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Harry Weinberger papers
1915-1944
MS 553
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
21.5
The papers consist of correspondence, legal papers, notes, and other materials documenting Weinberger's career as a lawyer who specialized in civil liberties cases and, later in his career, copyright law. The one hundred and sixteen (116) case files include legal briefs, writs, and memoranda prepared by Weinberger and his staff, and similar material prepared by opposing attorneys. Correspondence files include letters with clients and individuals interested in a specific case. Weinberger's clients included: Alexander Berkman, Grover Cleveland Bergdoll, Emma Goldman, and Eugene O'Neill. The papers also include a small number of Weinberg's short stories and plays and correspondence with his nephew, Warren Weinberger.
Weinberger, Harry, 1888-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Harold M. Wayne, 1944; Beatrice Mitherz, 2000; and Warren J. Weinberger, 2000.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Harry Weinberger was born in New York City in 1888. He attended New York University and was admitted to the bar in 1908. A staunch believer in civil liberties, Weinberger defended many aliens, immigrants, anarchists, and other radicals, including Emma Goldman and Alexander Berkman, whom he believed had been deprived of their rights. He also developed an expertise in copyright law, representing many writers, including Eugene O'Neill. Weinberger died in 1944.
Related Materials
For additional Weinberger papers see the following collections in the Yale Collection of American Literature, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library: Madeleine Elise (Reynier) Boyd; Louis Bromfield; James Hagan; Eugene O'Neill; Channing Pollock.
Papers related to Madame Rosika Schwimmer's suit against Upton Sinclair and William Fox are in the Schwimmer-Lloyd Collection, New York Public Library.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, legal papers, notes, and other materials documenting Weinberger's career as a lawyer who specialized in civil liberties cases and, later in his career, copyright law. The one hundred and sixteen (116) case files include legal briefs, writs, and memoranda prepared by Weinberger and his staff, and similar material prepared by opposing attorneys. Correspondence files include letters with clients and individuals interested in a specific case. Weinberger's clients included: Alexander Berkman, Grover Cleveland Bergdoll, Emma Goldman, and Eugene O'Neill. The papers also include a small number of Weinberg's short stories and plays and correspondence with his nephew, Warren Weinberger.
The Harry Weinberger Papers cover Weinberger's professional career from around 1915 until the early 1940s. In that time, Weinberger handled many types of cases, but he took a special interest in people whom he believed had been deprived of their civil liberties. As a result, Weinberger defended many aliens, immigrants, anarchists, and radicals. Two of Weinberger's most celebrated clients were the anarchists Emma Goldman and Alexander Berkman. Another client of Weinberger was the wealthy draft dodger, Grover Cleveland Bergdoll. Most of Weinberger's clients were, however, neither famous nor wealthy. Many were referred to Weinberger by service agencies like the American Civil Liberties Union, the League for Amnesty of Political Prisoners, and the Worker's Defense Fund.
In the later part of his career, Weinberger became an expert in copyright law, representing many writers, including Eugene O'Neill, in copyright and plagiarism suits. Weinberger corresponded with many prominent figures in connection with his legal work. His correspondents include Roger N. Baldwin, William A. Black, Alice Stone Blackwell, Harry M. Daugherty, Albert DeSilver, Elizabeth G. Flynn, Agnes Inglis, Daniel Kiefer, Robert M. LaFollette, Alvaro Obregon, Elmer Rice, Upton Sinclair, Lincoln Steffans, Norman Thomas, Frank P. Walsh, Thomas E. Watson and Stephen S. Wise.
The papers provide information on United States policies toward aliens, anarchists, and radicals in America during and after the first World War. The papers also contain material on United States immigration and deportation policies and important materials on Emma Goldman, Alexander Berkman, Ricardo Flores Magon, and Tom Mooney. There is, however, very little personal material on Weinberger in the papers. Biographical information can be found in Weinberger's "A Rebel's Interrupted Autobiography" published in the American Journal of Economics and Sociology in 1 October 1942.
Arrangement
The main accession is arranged in alphabetical order according to name of client. Two additions are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
Index of Correspondents
The following index is designed as an aid in finding significant letters and letters of prominent persons in this collection. Because the correspondence in the papers is grouped into more than one hundred sections, a correspondent may have letters filed in more than one section. Each of the selected correspondents is listed separately, followed by the name of the section or sections in which letters by that correspondent may be found. For example, the listing of Louis D. Brandeis appears as follows:
Brandeis, Louis D.
Brandeis, Louis D. -- Abrams, Jacob; The God of Vengeance; Goldman, Emma
This means that correspondence with Brandeis may be found in three sections: Jacob Abrams, The God of Vengeance, and Emma Goldman.
Index of Correspondents
Abbott, Leonard D. -- Abrams, Jacob; Goldman, Emma; Andrew Hamilton Memorial; Itzickson, Jacob; Rangel, Jesus M.; St. John, Vincent; Wu, Gray.
Abrahams, Israel -- The God of Vengeance
Abrams, Jacob -- Abrams, Jacob; Itzickson, Jacob
Actor's Equity Association -- Cape Playhouse Inc.; The God of Vengeance
Adams, H.S. -- The God of Vengeance
Allen, Henry J. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America -- Mooney, Tom
American Civil Liberties Union -- Abrams, Jacob; Bergdoll, Grover C.; Borghi, Armando; Bosco, Paul; Flores Magon, Ricardo; Garcia, Manuel Rey; The God of Vengeance; Goldman, Emma; Andrew Hamilton Memorial; Kramer, Louis; Martinez, Thomas; Potash, Iriving; Rangel, Jesus M.; St. John, Vincent; Shimuni, Petrus; Voss, Carl; Zogg, Nicholas S.
The American Dramatists -- Crumit, Frank; Stange, Hugh;Toller, Ernst
American Federation of Labor -- Abrams, Jacob; Rangel, Jesus M.; Rivera, Librado
American Freedom Foundation -- Abrams, Jacob
American Fund for Public Service -- The God of Vengenance; Rangel, Jesus M.
American Legion -- Bosco, Paul
The American Magazine -- The God of Vengeance
American Mercury -- Mooney, Tom
American Play Co. -- Selwyn and Co.
American Protection League -- The God of Vengeance
Andreyeff, Wasily -- Andreyeff, Wasily; Rasmussen, Rasmus; Zumpano, Salvatore
Ansell, Samuel T. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Anti-Vaccination League of America --Eckerold, Hagbard
Asch, Sholom -- The God of Venegeance
Ashleigh, Charles -- St. John, Vincent
Authors' League of America -- The God of Vengeance; Kreymborg, Alfred
Baker, Abby Scott -- Mooney, Tom
Baker, Newton D. -- Abrams, Jacob
Baker, Ray S. -- Abrams, Jacob
Baldazzi, Giovanni -- St. John, Vincent
Baldwin, Roger N. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.; Flores Magon, Ricardo; The God of Vengeance; Goldman, Emma; Andrew Hamilton Memorial; Kramer, Louis; Rangel, Jesus M.; St. John, Vincent
Ballentine, Harry -- Goldman, Emma
Ballentine, Stella -- Abrams, Jacob; Bales, William; Goldman, Emma
Bankhead, William B. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Barkley, Alben W. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Barton, Bruce -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Batten, Barton, Durstine, and Osborne -- Crumit, Frank
Beatty, Robert W. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Beck, James M. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Bergdoll, Berta -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Bergdoll, Emma C. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Bergdoll, Erwin -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Berger, Victor L. -- Borghi, Armando
Berkman, Alexander -- Goldman, Emma
Berman, Morris -- Andreytchine, George; Goldman, Emma; Itzickson, Jacob
Bernal, N.T. -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Bernstein, Rose -- Abrams, Jacob; Parsons, Robert; Rangel, Jesus M.; Rivera, Librado
Bigelow, Arthur S. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Bingham, Harry E. -- Bingham, Richard E.
Black, William A. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Blackwell, Alice Stone -- Flores Magon, Ricardo; Goldman, Emma; Rangel, Jesus M.; Rivera, Librado
Bloom, I. Mortimer -- The God of Vengeance
Blossom, Frederick A. -- Abrams, Jacob; Flores Magon, Ricardo; St. John, Vincent
Bobkin, Leon -- Derkach, Alexander
Boni, Albert -- Cheney, Sheldon
Borah, William E. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.; Borghi, Armando; Flores Magon, Ricardo; Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Boston, Charles A. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Bowman, George A. -- Feng Shun Exhibition Corporation
Brainard, Clinton T. -- Goldman, Emma
Brandeis, Louis D. -- Abrams, Jacob; The God of Vengeance; Goldman, Emma
Brannin, Carl -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Butler, Henry F. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Butler, Nicholas M. -- The God of Vengeance
Callahan, James D. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Calles, P. Elias -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Cane, Melville H. -- The God of Vengeance; Kozlenko, William; Kreynborg, Alfred; Provincetown Players
Capers, William T. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Capper, Arthur -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Carrillo, A.P. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Castleton, Samuel M. -- Abrams, Jacob; Bosco, Paul; Goldman, Emma; Kramer, Louis; Zogg, Nicholas S.
Celler, Emanuel -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Century Play Co. -- Selwyn and Co.; Stange, Hugh
Cerf, Bennett -- Theatre Alliance, Inc.
Chafee, Zachariah -- Abrams, Jacob; The God of Vengeance
Chisolm, B. Ogden -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Chiu, Roy -- Wu, Gray
Chow, Woo -- Wu, Gray
Christensen, Otto -- Andreytchine, George; St. John, Vincent
Ciafalo, Andrea -- Campeo, Tomaso; Ciafalo, Andrea
Cisneros, Abraham -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Citizens Amnesty Committee -- Abrams, Jacob
The Civic Club -- The God of Vengeance
Clark, A. Mortimer -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Clark, Barrett H. -- Kreymborg, Alfred; Toller, Ernst
Clemens, Addie -- Goldman, Emma
Cline, Charles -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Coffee, Harry B. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Cohen, Herbert -- Cheneky, Lena; Kramer, Louis
Cohen, Theodore -- College Entrance Book Co.
Cohn, Michael A. -- Abrams, Jacob; Andreyeff, Wasily; Becker, Morris; Goldman, Emma; Kramer, Louis; Parsons, Robert; Rasmussen, Rasmus; Wu, Gray
Colcord, Lincoln -- Abrams, Jacob
Colquitt, O.B. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Comitato Difesa Borghi -- Borghi, Armando
Comitato Italiano Pro-Vittime Politiche -- Vito, Mariani
Commins, Louis H. -- Goldman, Emma
Commins, Saxe -- Goldman, Emma
Conboy, Martin -- The God of Vengeance
Connor, John H. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Conway, William O. -- The God of Vengeance
Cook, George Cram -- Provincetown Players
Copeland, Royal S. -- Borghi, Armando
Crane, Frank -- The God of Vengeance
Creel, George -- Abrams, Jacobs; Goldman, Emma
Crump, Richard -- The God of Vengeance
Culberson, Charles A. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Dalzell, George W. -- Goldman, Emma
Dana, Henry W. L. -- Abrams, Jacob
Danziger, Samuel -- Rangel, Jesus M.; Vaccination
Darrow, Clarence -- Goldman, Emma; St. John, Vincent
Daugherty, Harry M. -- Abrams, Jacob; Flores Magon, Ricardo; Ross, Edwin J.; St. John, Vincent; Zogg, Nicholas S.
Davidson, T. W. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Davis, James J. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Davis, John W. -- Bales, William B.; Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Davis, Philip R. -- Jones, John A.
The Day -- Goldman, Emma
Debs, Eugene V. -- Abrams, Jacob; Rangel, Jesus M.
Debs, Theodore -- Rangel, Jesus M.
De Casseres, Benjamin -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Deeter, Jasper -- Provincetown Players
de la Huerta, Adolfo -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Dennett, Mary Ware -- Alexander Hamilton Memorial
De Silver, Albert -- Abrams, Jacob; Bosco, Paul; The God of Vengeance; Goldman, Emma; Kaplunoff, Matthew; Kramer, Louis; Rangel, Jesus M.; St. John, Vincent; Wu, Gray; Zumpano, Salvatore
Deutsch, Bernard S. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Dintenfass, Mark M. -- The God of Vengeance; Troy, Lillian Scott
Dix, Mark H. -- The God of Vengeance
Dodd, Mead, and Co. -- Kozlenko, William; Watson, Thomas E.
Dodge, Wendell P. -- Feng Shun Exhibition Corporation
Dorf, Max -- Bottvinick, Eva
Doubleday, Doran and Co. -- Collins, Delores L.
Doubleday, Page and Co. -- Goldman, Emma; Watson, Thomas E.
Downey, Sheridan -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Durante, Jimmy -- Kreymborg, Alfred
Dukee, Harris S. -- Abrams, Jacob; Becker, Morris
Eastman, Max -- Andreytchine, George; Goldman, Emma
Eisemann, Alex -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Elner, Charles H. -- Cheney, Sheldon
Ernst, Morris L. -- The God of Vengeance
Erwin, Charles W. -- Borghi, Armando; Garcia, Manuel Rey; The God of Vengeance
Evans, Earle W. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Ewing, H. W. -- Goldman, Emma
Faddis, Charles I. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Fadiman, Clifton -- Cheney, Sheldon
Farr, Chester -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Fat, Lew -- Wu, Gray
Feldman, Gustave B. -- Kreymborg, Alfred
Ferguson, Miriam A. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Fish, Hamilton -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Fitzgerald, Cora E. -- Cape Playhouse Inc.
Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor – Becker, Morris; Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor; Magon, Ricardo Flores; The God of Vengeance; Goldman, Emma; Newlander, Carl; Provincetown Players; Rasmussen, Rasmus; Sergi, Salvatore; Sernaker, Bernard; Slivinski, Victor; Troy, Lillian Scott; Voss, Carl
Fleischer, Sidney R. -- Stange, Hugh
Flores Magon, Enrique -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Flores Magon, Jesus -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Flynn, Elizabeth G. – Abrams, Jacob; Bosco, Paul; Feltman, Emile; Flores Magon, Ricardo; Garcia, Manuel Rey; The God of Vengeance; Itzickson, Jacob; Jones, John A.; Kaplunoff, Matthew; Krispens, William; Potash, Irving; Rangel, Jesus M.; St. John, Vincent; Voss, Carl; Zumpano, Salvatore
France, Joseph I. -- Abrams, Joseph; Bosco, Paul
Francioni, Albert -- Zumpano, Salvatore
Frankfurter, Felix -- Abrams, Jacob; The God of Vengeance
Freehill, James E. -- Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor
The Freeman -- The God of Vengeance
Freie Arbeiter Stimme -- The God of Vengeance
Freiheit -- Toller, Ernst
Gaige, Crosby -- Selwyn and Co.
Garcia, Manuel Rey -- Garcia, Manuel Rey; St. John, Vincent
Garcia, R.B. -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Garcia, Manuel Rey -- Garcia, Manuel Rey; St. John, Vincent
Garner, John -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Garrigues, Ellen -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Gartz, Kate C. -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Gassner, John W. -- Cheney, Sheldon
Geddes, Donald P. -- Kreymborg, Alfred
Geddes, Virgil -- Provincetown Players
General Defense Committee -- Andreytchine, George; Rangel, Jesus M.; St. John, Vincent; Wu, Gray
Gershkowitz, Sarah -- Sergi, Salvatore
Geyer, Lee E. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Gilbert, Cass -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Gilman, George H. -- The God of Vengeance
Girard, Thomas L. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Gladstone, Joseph -- The God of Vengeance
Glaspell, Susan -- Provincetown Players
Gneiser, G. A. -- Bosco, Paul
Goldberg, Isaac -- The God of Vengeance
Goldman, Mayer C. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Gompers, Samuel -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Gonzales, Jesus -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Goss, Gertrude A. -- Latson, William R. C.
Goss, Walter W. -- Latson, William R. C.
Granick, Alexander -- The God of Vengeance
Grant, Percy S. -- Jager, Henry
Grau, Joseph -- Fernandez, Jose R.
Grosser, David -- Goldman, Emma
Grosser, Philip B. -- Goldman, Emma; Rangel, Jesus M.
Grossman, Moses H. -- Provincetown Players
Guffey, Joseph F. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Haberman, Roberto -- Flores Magon, Ricardo; Rangel, Jesus M.; Rivera, Librado
Hague, Robert L. -- Crumit, Frank
Hall, Albert -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Hall, Bolton -- Goldman, Emma
Hall, Covington -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Hall, W. C. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Hallet, Louis -- Three Artists Little Theatre
Hammer, Julius -- Jager, Henry
Hand, Learned -- Bales, William B.; The God of Vengeance
Hapgood, Norman -- Abrams, Jacob; Flores Magon, Ricardo; St. John, Vincent
Harby, M. E. -- The God of Vengeance
Harcourt, Brace and Co. -- Barnes, Djuna; Kozlenko, William; Kreymborg, Alfred
Harding, Warren G. -- Flores Magon, Ricardo; Rivera, Librado; St. John, Vincent
Harlan, Esther -- St. John, Vincent
Harness, Forest A. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Harpers and Brothers -- Watson, Thomas E.
Harrington, Thomas F. -- Crumit, Frank
Harris, Frank -- Goldman, Emma
Harris, Maurice H. -- The God of Vengeance
Harvey, Alice D. -- Goldman, Emma
Health Culture -- Latson, William R. C.
Hecla Press -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Hennessy, Charles O'Connor -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Henry Holt and Co. -- Watson, Thomas E.
Hickok, Guy C. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Higgins, Charles M. -- Ekerold, Hagbard; Thorpe, Herbert A.; Vaccination
Hill, Frank -- Cheney, Sheldon
Hiss, Alger -- Goldman, Emma
Hobby, W. P. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Holmes, John H. -- The God of Vengeance; St. John, Vincent
Hoover, J. Edgar -- Bergdoll, Grover C.; Itzickson, Jacob
Hopkins, Arthur -- Provincetown Players
Houghton, Miflin Co. -- Watson, Thomas E.
Huddleson, George -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Hughes, William J. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Huntington, Henry S. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Hurst, Fannie -- The God of Vengeance
Hylan, John F. -- The God of Vengeance
Idar, C. N. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Inglis, Agnes -- Abrams, Jacob; Bergdoll, Grover C.; Goldman, Emma; St. John, Vincent
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Irish Progressive League -- Troy, Lillian Scott
Isaacson, Jacob -- Itzickson, Jacob
Italian Defense Committee -- St. John, Vincent
Italian Defense League -- Buzzi, Alfredo
Jaffe, Sam -- The God of Vengeance
Jefferson City Prison -- Goldman, Emma
Jewish Daily Forward -- The God of Vengeance; Goldman, Emma
Johnson, Albert -- Bosco, Paul; Kaplunoff, Matthew; St. John, Vincent
Johnson, Hiram W. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.; St. John, Vincent
Johnson, Royal C. -- Bosco, Paul
Johnston, Mercer G. -- Mooney, Tom; Rangel, Jesus M.
Joint Amnesty Committee -- Josephson, Aaron
Jones, J. Gordon -- Becker, Morris; Goldman, Emma
Jones, William F. -- Carruthers, Gloria
Joyce, Frank P. -- Zogg, Nicholas
Jury, William -- Troy, Lillian Scott
Kahn, Otto H. -- Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor; The God of Vengeance
Kansas State Board of Health -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Kauser, Alice -- The God of Vengeance
Keiper, Frank -- Cheney, Sheldon
Kelly, Gertrude B. -- Troy, Lillian Scott
Kelly, Harry -- Goldman, Emma; Wu, Gray
Kelly, James M. -- O'Brien, Charles M.
Kelly, M. Clyde -- St. John, Vincent
Kennan, Ellen A. -- Goldman, Emma
Kenton, Edna -- Provincetown Players
Kiefer, Daniel -- Abrams, Jacob; Bergdoll, Grover C.; Goldman, Emma; Rangel, Jesus M.; St. John, Vincent
King, Alexander C. -- Abrams, Jacob
Kisliuk, Lillian -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Klawans, Bernard -- Crumit, Frank
Knight, Al H. -- Crumit, Frank
Knoblanch, Mary -- The God of Vengeance
Knopf, Alfred A. -- Goldman, Emma
Kopp, Harry -- The God of Vengeance
Kovner, Hilda -- Abrams, Jacob; Itzickson, Jacob; Kramer, Louis; Mariani, Vito; Perruchon, Peter; Rangel, Jesus M.; Rivera, Librado; Zogg, Nicholas
Krakeur, Richard -- Crumit, Frank
Krass, Nathan -- The God of Vengeance
Lachowsky, Hyman -- Abrams, Jacob
La Follette, Robert M. -- Abrams, Jacob; Bergdoll, Grover C.; Bosco, Paul; Flores Magon, Ricardo; Goldman, Emma
La Guardia, Fiorella -- Abrams, Jacob; Borghi, Armando; Rangel, Jesus M.
Lane, Hunter -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Langer, Lawrence -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Langworth, S. B. -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Lara, Blas -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Latson, Gertrude -- Latson, William R. C.
Law, Jack -- St. John, Vincent
Law, Madeleine -- St. John, Vincent
Lawton, Nathan O. -- Latson, William R. C.
League for Mutual Aid -- Rangel, Jesus M.
League for the Amnesty Political Prisoners -- Daniel, David S.; Flores Magon, Ricardo; Newlander, Carl; Sergi, Salvatore; Sernaker, Bernard; Slivinski, Victor; Voss, Carl
Lega Italiana di Difesa Operaia -- Mariani, Vito
Lewisohn, Alice -- Abrams, Jacob
Lewisohn, Irene -- Abrams, Jacob
Liberty Defense Union -- Derkach, Alexander
Library of Congress -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial; Kreymborg, Alfred; Latson, William R. C.
Lilley, Edward C. -- Crumit, Frank
Lipman, Samuel -- Abrams, Jacob
J. B. Lippincott Co. -- Watson, Thomas E.
Liveright Publishing Co. -- Barnes, Djuna; Gollomb, Joseph
Lodge, Henry Cabot -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
London, Meyer -- St. John, Vincent
Longmans, Green and Co. -- Cheney, Sheldon
Lowe, Caroline -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Lowensohn, Mina -- Itzickson, Jacob
Lunsford, J. J. -- Latson, William R. C.
McClure Newspaper Syndicate -- Goldman, Emma
McCracken, Robert T. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
MacGowen, Kenneth -- Provincetown Players
McGraw Hill Book Co. -- College Book Entrance Co.
Mac Kaye, Percy -- The God of Vengeance
McKenzie, Edwin V. -- Goldman, Emma
MacMillan Co. -- Gollomb, Joseph
McNutt, Maxwell -- Goldman, Emma
Madden, Richard J. -- Crumit, Frank
Maggio, Andrew -- Vazzani, Stefano
Manhattan Single Tax Club -- Simpson, Samuel W.
Mantle, Burns -- Cheney, Sheldon
Marcontonio, Vito -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Markham, Edwin -- The God of Vengeance
Marshall, Louis -- The God of Vengeance; Goldman, Emma
Martin, George W. -- Cape Playhouse Inc.
Martin, Pedro -- Fernandez, Jose R.
Martin, W. P. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Mason, William E. -- Bosco, Paul
Massachusetts, Commonwealth of -- Cape Playhouse Inc.
May, Andrew J. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Mead, James M. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Mencken, H. L. -- The God of Vengeance; Goldman, Emma
Merchant, Walter -- George, Anthony
Merlin, M. J. -- Becker, Morris; Goldman, Emma
Merritt, Matthew J. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures, Legal Department -- Carruthers, Gloria; Collins, Delores L.; Selwyn and Co.; Stange, Hugh
Mickle, W. H. -- Latson, William R. C.
Mielziner, Jo -- Cape Playhouse Inc.
Miller, Eugene M. -- Latson, William R. C.
Millhound, John E. -- Goldman, Emma
Minor, Robert -- Goldman, Emma
Mish, Solomon -- Mooney, Tom
Missouri State Prisons -- Abrams, Jacob; Goldman, Emma
Mitchell, John P. -- Ekerold, Hagbard
Mooney, Rena -- Mooney, Tom
Mooney, Tom -- Goldman, Emma; Mooney, Tom
Moore, Raymond -- Cape Playhouse Inc.
Morones, Luis N. -- Flores Magon, Ricardo; Rangel, Jesus M.
Morris, Robert C. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Munguia, Refugio R. -- Rivera, Librado
Munsell, Warren P. -- Carruthers, Gloria
Murdock, William C. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Murphy, Frank -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Myers, Robert P. -- Crumit, Frank
Nathanson, Rose -- Becker, Morris
Nathanson, William -- Goldman, Emma
The Nation -- Abrams, Jacob; The God of Vengeance; Goldman, Emma; Mooney, Tom
National Civil Liberties Bureau -- Goldman, Emma; Itzickson, Jacob
National League for Medical Freedom -- Ekerold, Hagbard; Vaccination
The Nautilus -- Latson, William R. C.
Nealon, Joseph M. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Nearing, Scott -- Abrams, Jacob
Nebeker, Frank K. -- St. John, Vincent
Neff, Pat M. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Nelles, Walter -- O'Brien, Charles M.
Nelson, Walter M. -- Goldman, Emma
Neumann, Henry -- The God of Vengeance
New Jersey, Essex County Penitentiary -- Kramer, Louis
New Republic -- Mooney, Tom
New York City District Attorney -- George, Anthony; Mariani, Vito; O'Brien, Charles M.; Wu, Gray
New York City Magistrates' Court -- Cohen, Maurice; Provincetown Players; Purdy, Elias
New York City Parole Commission -- Wu, Gray
New York City Police Department -- Ciafalo, Andrea; George, Anthony; Messinger, Joe
New York County Lawyers' Association -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
New York State -- Bingham, Richard E.; Crumit, Frank; Ekerold, Hagbard; Feng Shun Exhibition Corporation; Provincetown Players
New York State District Attorney -- Goldman, Emma
Norman, Dorothy -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Norman, Lucille -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Northam, W. Arthur -- Troy, Lillian Scott
Novikoff, Ivan -- Dekach, Alexander
Novoye Russkoye Slovo -- Goldman, Emma
Nye, Gerald P. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Obenchain, Lida C. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Obregon, Alvaro -- Flores Magon, Ricardo; Rangel, Jesus M.; Rivera, Librado
O'Connell, Daniel -- Goldman, Emma